Guide to the Cornell Migrant Program campus collection,1953-2006.
Cornell Migrant Program campus collection,1953-2006.
- Series III. Programs
  - Agricultural Careers Subcontract with Rural Opportunities, Inc., 1985 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Albany Office - Migrant Program (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Farmworker Responses to "Safety Net" Question by Paul Lehman, Agriculture Agent, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Migrant Medical Services Education, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Cornell Migrant Education, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Immigration Laws, 1985-1994 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Migrant Education Proposal, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - New York State Migrant Education Annual Training, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Change for Migrant Farmworkers, 1986-05-14-1986-05-15 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Change for Migrant Farmworkers, 1986-11-18 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Migrant Health and Nutrition, 1986 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Health and Nutrition, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Migrant Education, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Adult Literacy, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Change for Migrant Farmworkers, 1987-04-09 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Dislocated Farmworkers - New York State, 1986-1987 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Student Service-Learning Project (ACTION) Kathy Fox (Castania), 1987-1988 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Migrant Health, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Migrant Education, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Cornell Migrant Program and Human Service Studies, 1988 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - ACTION, 1988-1989 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Albany Office Sub-budgets (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Migrant Education, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Migrant Education, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Migrant Education, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Orange County (New York) Letter from Kay Embrey to R. David Smith, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Farm Health and Safety, 1990-1992 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - Migrant Early Childhood Education Project (not funded), 1990 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Migrant Farmworkers of Wayne County, New York: A Collection of Oral Histories from the Back Roads, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Pre-School Proposal, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Legal Clinics - Wayne County New York State - Kay Embrey, 1991-1997 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Migrant Education, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Migrant Education, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Home School Joint Cornell/Geneseo Project, 1992-1993 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Farmworker Citizenship Campaign (Bureau of Refugee and Immigration Affairs) - Embrey, 1992-1994 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Migrant Education, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Becoming a Citizen, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Liberty Partnership Program (New York State Education) - Embrey and Castania (not funded), 1994 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Farmworkers/St. Catherine of Siena (Ithaca, New York), 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Vocational Rehabilitation Service Project with ILR (not funded), 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Sustainable Agriculture, 1994-2001 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Immigration Laws, 1994-2004 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Migrant Summer Science Camp (not funded - source eliminated) - Dr. Eloy Rodriguez, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Training for Reducing Risks and Increasing Capacity - Kathy Castania/Steve Goggin, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Migrant Education, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - New York State Comprehensive Assistance Center - SUNY Albany, Syracuse, Lehman, Columbia (not funded), 1995 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Migrant Farmworker Children: Educational Research and Policy (Hatch Funds) Conroy, Ewert and Engman (not funded), 1996 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Migrant Education, 1996 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Fund for Rural America (USDA) (not submitted) - Engman, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Migrant Education, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - FAITH project - Kay Embrey, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Cornell Farmworker Institute (Proposed) Kellogg Foundation, 1997-1999 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Strategic Plans - Cornell Migrant Program and Youth, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Collaboration Cornell Migrant Program with Pilar Parra, 1998-2003 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Migrant Education, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - H2-A, Guest Worker Programs, 1998-2002 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Telephone Access for Migrant Farmworkers (New York), 1998-1999 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Child Labor Update - Kay Embrey, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Migrant Education, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - Migrant Education Evaluation, 1999-2002 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Civil Service Employees Association (CSEA) Presentation - H. Engman and K. Embrey, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Migrant Education Final Fiscal Report (Example), 2000 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Migrant Education, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Immigrants and AFL-CIO, 2000 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Arrangement and Description of Cornell Migrant Program Records (Kay Embrey), 2000-01 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Immigrants in Rural Communities - Max Pfeffer, Kay Embrey, Pilar Parra, 2000-2004 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Legal Education For Women - Cornell / Farmworker Legal Services, 2002-2004 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Migrant Education, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Workers to Farmers Project - Kay Embrey (not funded), 2003 (Box 16, Folder 39)
  - New York State Migrant Education 2002-2007 (Ended by Cornell, 2004), 2002-2007 (Box 16, Folder 40)
  - Farm Labor - Miscellaneous, 2001 (Box 16, Folder 41)
- Series IV. Herb Engman
  - Initial Appointment of Herbert J. Engman, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Herb Engman and Steve Johnson, 1973-1977 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Herb Engman, 1976-01-1976-05 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Herb Engman, 1976-06-1976-12 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Migrant Task Force (New York) - Letter Engman to Chet Provorse, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Herb Engman, 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Lucinda Noble (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Letter Re: Future of the Migrant Program - Engman to Sid Cleveland, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Herb Engman, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Herb Engman, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Peter Chi - Health Research (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Herb Engman, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Herb Engman, 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Herb Engman, 1986-1988 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Herb Engman, 1989-1991 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Herb Engman, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Herb Engman, 1994-1995 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Herb Engman, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence - Herb Engman and Steve Goggin, 1996-1999 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence Herb Engman, 1998-2002 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence Herb Engman, 2003-2005 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Engman Personnel, 1973-1999 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Engman Job Searches, 1975-1977 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Resignation of H. Engman from Migrant Program, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Engman Hiring - Department of Human Development and Family Studies, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Youth Development Articles - Herb Engman (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Extension Management and Information System (EMIS) (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Migrants: Exploited, Neglected and Discriminated Against - Engman, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Health Presentations - Engman, 1992-1993 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Engman Presentations - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Engman - Rural Health Presentation - Conference, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Arturo Rodriguez (President, United Farm Workers), 1995 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Engman Presentation - East Coast Migrant Stream Health Forum, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Engman letter to Ithaca Journal Re: Immigration Enforcement, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Engman - Farmworker Hall of Fame, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Strategic Plan, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - D. Merrill Ewert (Director of Cornell Cooperative Extension), 1999 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - United Nations Presentation - Herb Engman, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Engman Class Presentations (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Union Community College Presentation, 2003 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Controversy Re: Engman comment on AgJobs Bill, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Cornell Extension Club, 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Field Study (Cornell), 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Cornell University As Employer Committee, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Empowerment Study Group, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Plan of Work for Cornell Cooperative Extension, 1983-1987 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Herb Engman, Department Extension Leader - Renovations, 1984-1988 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Cornell Institute for Social and Economic Research (CISR), 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Tompkins County, New York Focus, 1988-1989 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Community and Rural Development Institute (CARDI), 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Kellogg Grant - CARDI, 1990-1992 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Community and Rural Development Institute (CARDI), 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Community and Rural Development Institute (CARDI), 1993-1999 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Empowerment - Mon Cochran et.al., 1984-1987 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Plan of Work for Cornell Cooperative Extension, 1988-1991 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Human Development Funding from Cooperative Extension, 1988-1992 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Human Development Budget Committee and Cornell Migrant Program Cut, 1990-1991 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Plan of Work for Cornell Cooperative Extension, 1992-1995 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Human Development Funding from Cooperative Extension, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Human Development Funding from Cooperative Extension, 1995-2003 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Integration of Cornell Migrant Program Within Cornell Cooperative Extension (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - External Review Report - Department of Human Development, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Extension Work in Human Development, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Plan of Work for Cornell Cooperative Extension, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Herb Engman, Department Extension Leader, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Paul Eberts (Rural Sociology) (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Strategic Plan - Department of Human Development, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Agricultural Work Force, Family and Community Program Work Team, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Land Grant Impact Statements, 2001-2002 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Cornell Cooperative Extension Funding (Smith-Lever), 2001-2006 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - CULSAR and Farmworkers, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Migrant Farmworkers and the Cornell Community - Kanuga and McKay, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Association of Cornell Cooperative Extension Educators, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Cornell Student Involvement with Farmworkers, 2002-2004 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Alternative Spring Break with Farmworkers, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Re-envisioning el campo: Justice for Farmworkers, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Subseries IVa. Reappointment Reviews, Annual Reports
    - Herbert J. Engman Reappointment Review, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Herbert J. Engman Reappointment Review, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Herbert J. Engman Reappointment Review, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Herbert J. Engman Reappointment Review (Folder 1), 1994 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Herbert J. Engman Reappointment Review (2 - Grants), 1994 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Herbert J. Engman Reappointment Review (3 - Publications), 1994 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Herbert J. Engman Reappointment Review, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Annual Reports - Herb Engman, 1974-1990 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Annual Reports - Herb Engman, 1991-2006 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Series V. Staff Correspondence and Programs
  - Kay Embrey - Original Appointment, 1980 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Kay Embrey - Annual Reports, 1981-2000 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Kay Embrey - Programs, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Kay Embrey - Programs, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Kay Embrey - Communications and Programs, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Kay Embrey - Communications and Programs, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Kay Embrey - Communications and Programs, 1986-1988 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Martin Luther King Award - Kay Embrey and Kathy Fox (Castania), 1989 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Kay Embrey - Communications and Programs, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Kay Embrey - Communications and Programs, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Kay Embrey - Communications and Programs, 1994-1996 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities (Kay Embrey Fellowship), 1993 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Kay Embrey - Communications and Programs, 1997-1999 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Kay Embrey - Communications and Programs, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Kay Embrey - National Model of Farmworker Coordination Award, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Hall of Fame - Kay Embrey (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Kay Embrey Retirement, 2005 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Adult Literacy - Kathy Fox (Castania), 1981-1987 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Kathy Fox (Castania) Reports (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Kathy Castania Fox - Programs, 1982-1990 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Migrant Oral History Project - Kathy Fox (Castania), 1985-1991 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Kathy Castania - Programs, 1991-1995 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Kathy Castania, 1996-2003 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Kathy Castania Fox - Papers, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Kathy Fox (Castania) Study Leave, 1989-1991 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Kathy Castania - Florence Halpern Extension/Outreach Award, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Diversity Education and USDA - Kathy Castania, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Kathy Castania - Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Award, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Kathy Castania - Farmworker Hall of Fame, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Kathy Castania - National Extension Diversity Award, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Kathy Castania Retirement, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Betty Garcia Mathewson - Correspondence and Programs, 1994-2002 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Betty Garcia Mathewson - Language Interpretation Guidelines (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Betty Garcia Mathewson - Community Development National Conference, 2003 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Stephen E. Goggin, 1980- (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Molly Nye Annual Reports, 1982-1997 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Mary (Molly) K. Nye (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Jay Drake - Annual Reports, 1981-1992 (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Alannah Fitzgerald, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Matthew J. Gallelli, 1996 (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Wilfred Messier, 1987 (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Mary Heidenreich, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Pat Ward Annual Reports, 1984-1997 (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Patricia Ward (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Nancy Robilotto (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Vonda Royce, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Onaje Benjamin, 2000 (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Sharron A. Callahan-Sims (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Faith (Fay) Richardson, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 49)
  - Gail Maassen (Jackson) - Cornell Migrant Program Support, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 50)
  - Eduardo Gonzalez, 2001-2003 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Staff Monthly Reports (7/89-7/90), 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Staff, 1979-2002 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Contacts - Wayne County Special Migrant Project (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Program Ideas - Jennie Birckmayer, 1967-1976 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Jennie Birckmayer, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Migrant Youth Program - Orange County, David Dik, 1969 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Financial Matters - Cornell Budget, 1971-1982 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Financial Correspondence, 1982-2000 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Grant Summaries - H. Engman, K. Embrey, K. Castania, 1983-2004 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Financial Correspondence, 2001-2004 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Funding Closeout - Cornell Migrant Program, 2004 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Farm Workers Community Center (Goshen, NY) (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Community Programs for Seasonal Farmworkers - Wayne County, New York, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Child Care for Migrants Proposals, 1973 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Day Haul - Buffalo, South Jersey, Philadelphia - Steve Johnson, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Human Ecology ID 325- Student Papers, 1973-1974 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Infants and Toddlers - Sodus, Columbia, 1974 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Human Ecology ID 325- Seasonal Workers: Problems and Programs (Dik, Johnson, Engman), 1974 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Project Information, 1974-1975 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Conference Presentations - Steve Johnson, 1974-1976 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Wayne Self-Development Center - Lyons, New York, 1974-1976 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence - Steve Johnson, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Williamson (New York) Community Center, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Learn and Earn - Cornell, PFI, New York State Education, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Wayne Sounding Board, 1975-1981 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Clinton County Rural Development - Steve Johnson, 1975-1976 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Columbia County (New York), 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Migrant Health (New York State Dept. Health) Niagara County, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - OSHA vs. Walter C. Mehlenbacher, Prof. John Hartman Response, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Wyoming County (New York), 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Unionization of Farm Labor - Steve Johnson, Herb Engman, 1976-1977 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence - Bruce John, Sherilyn Morrison, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Entry for Agriculture and Life Sciences Annual Report - Stephen P. Johnson, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Inter-Agency Coordinating Committee on Migrant and Rural Poor, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Chester Provorse (letter to by Dennis U. Fisher), 1977 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Wayne County (New York) Schools, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Hope Village Education/Recreation, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Proposed Early Childhood Migrant Education, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Community Resource Development (New York State), 1977-1981 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence - Bruce John, Sherilyn Morrison, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Steve Johnson Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Migrant Farmworker Background, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Migrant Health (New York State) - Niagara County, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Migrant Legal Action (Washington, D.C.), 1978 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Report of Activities for Migratory Workers in Wyoming County (New York), 1979 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Potential Funding Sources, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Agriculture and Markets - Kim Blot, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Human Service Studies - Migrant Programs, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - New York State Parks, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Rural and Farm Life Development, 1979-1982 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Empire Chapter Community Development Society, 1979-1984 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - 4-H For Migrant Farmworker Children in California (1979), Michigan (1984) (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - 4-H Migrant Children Summer Camps, 1980-1983 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Agricultural Labor, 1980-1985 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Dairy Farm Listing for Migrant Education Census, 1980-1990 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Apple Picking (Guide for Farmworkers) Kay Embrey, 1980-1989 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Tractor Driving Project, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Cornell Migrant/4-H Summer Camp Program, 1981 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Haitian Farmworkers, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Immigration Law Enforcement, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Adult Literacy Project - Kathy Fox and Kay Embrey, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Program Development in Nonformal Education - David Monk and J. Lin Compton, 1983-1984 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Tour of Eastern New York State, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Descriptions, 1987, 1989, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Strategic Plan, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Cornell Migrant Program Staff Meetings, 1998-2004 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Chris and Eve Pawelski's emails pertaining to the Cornell Migrant Program, 2007 (Box 53, Folder 1-4)
- Series VI. Public Policy
  - Public Policy Involvement - Herb Engman (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Legislative Alerts (Cornell Office of Government Affairs) Examples (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Agricultural Affiliates (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - New York's Agricultural Districts - Don White, Kenneth Gardner, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Farm Bureau Objection to "Harvest of Shame", 1973 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Response of John D. Hartman to Readers' Digest Article, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - The Farm Labor Situation (CA) - John D. Hartman, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Model Legislation for Farmworkers - RNYFO (R.O.I.), 1979 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Bishop Matthew H. Clark's Visit to Cornell, 1980-05-07 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Minimum Wage for Farmworkers (New York State), 1980-1982 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Black Agricultural Laborers in Oneida County, New York - Letter Engman to De Amicis, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Campbell Soup Boycott - Rural New York Farmworker Opp., 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Public Policy Education - Alan Hahn (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Public Policy Education, 1983-1992 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - "Pastoral Letter...and the U.S. Economy" (National Conference of Catholic Bishops), 1985 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - New York Farm Bureau Policies, 1985-2004 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Association of Farmworker Opportunity Programs (Examples), 1989-1990 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Gov. Mario Cuomo's Task Force on Agricultural Employment, Education and Labor (1), 1989 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - The Distribution of Farm Program Payments, 1987 (USDA), 1990 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Agricultural Labor Markets in New York State and Implications for Labor Policy - Report, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Legislative Support for Farmworker Issue / Public Policy Training, 1990-1997 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Farmworkers and the Public Policy Process (New York State), 1993 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - New York Agriculture in the Classroom (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - New York FarmNet Creation, 1985-2000 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - Public Policy - Cooperative Extension (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Farmworker Advocacy Day (New York State), 1998 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Farmworker Advocacy Day (New York State), 1999 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Farmworker Advocacy Day (New York State), 2000 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Farmworker Advocacy Day, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Farmworker Advocacy Day, 2002 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Farmworker Advocacy Day, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Farmworker March and Advocacy Day, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Farmworker Advocacy Day, 2006 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Agricultural Organization Lobbying (New York State), 1998-2004 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Testimony - Joint Legislation Hearings on Farmworkers, 2000 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Collective Bargaining for Farmworkers, 2001-2004 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Farmworker Justice Fund Report, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Enlightened Markets (Fair Trade) New York State, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Fair Trade Examples, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Farm Bureau (New York State) State Policies (Example), 2003 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Agricultural Immigration Policy and Implications, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Farm Subsidies (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Farmworker "Omnibus" Bill - New York State Assembly, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Attorney General's (New York State) Opinion on Access to Labor Camps, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Public Policy Education Statement of Principle for the Cornell Cooperative Extension System, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Public Policy Education Task Force, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Interstate Migrant Education Council, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Hearing of the Joint Legislative Task Force on Farmworker Issues, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Herb Engman Testimony - New York State Joint Legislative Task Force, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - Public Policy Education - Materials (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Cornell Campus Discussions of Farmworker Issues, 1994-1995 (Box 12, Folder 26)